Register to The Quincy Porter Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Porter's Works, 1914-1966; Series X; 24 Boxes
  - Day Dreams, piano [for earlier version of this, see Eight Pieces for Bill, 1941-1942], 1957; lb: (Box 56, Folder 125)
    2 Merion Music publication 1958
  - Mad Woman of Chaillot, a musical adaptation, [1957?]; lb: (Box 56, Folder 126)
  - String Quartet No. 9, 1958; lb: (Box 56, Folder 127)
  - New England Episodes, 1958; lb: (Box 56, Folder 128)
  - New England Episodes, 1958; lb: (Box 56, Folder 129)
  - Passacaglia, from New England Episodes, lb: (Box 56, Folder 129)
  - Fugue, from New England Episodes, lb: (Box 56, Folder 129)
  - Concerto, harpsichord & orchestra, 1959; lb: (Box 57, Folder 130)
  - Concerto, harpsichord & orchestra, 1959; lb: (Box 57, Folder 131)
  - Music for the Elizabethan Club, 1959
    - 1. Horn Call, typescript, score (Box 57, Folder 132)
    - 2. Trumpet/Horn Calls from Antony & Cleopatra, typescript, score (Box 57, Folder 132)
    - 3. Drinking Song from Antony & Cleopatra, for winds, typescript, parts (Box 57, Folder 132)
    - 4. Masque and Entre-Acte, lb: (Box 57, Folder 132)
    - 5. Three Elizabethan Songs, pages of text (Box 57, Folder 133)
      - "The God of Love", holograph, score
      - "When I Was Fair and Young" ["Queen Elizabeth's Song"], lb:
      - "Spring" ["Cuckoo Song"], lb:
    - Yale University Press publication [hard cover, all three songs]
    - Music for the Elizabethan Club, 1959; holograph, score & typescript, parts
  - Concerto [Concertino] for Wind Orchestra, 1959; lb: (Box 58, Folder 134)
    C.F. Peters Corp. publication 1959
  - Divertimento, woodwind quintet, 1960; lb: (Box 58, Folder 135)
  - Divertimento, woodwind quintet, 1960; lb: (Box 58, Folder 136)
  - [Kansas Piece], 1960; lb: (Box 58, Folder 137)
  - Wedding Fantasy on Melodies by Lucy Coolidge, 1960; positive photocopy, typescript score (Box 58, Folder 138)
  - Quintet, harpsichord & strings, 1961; lb: (Box 58, Folder 139)
  - Quintet, harpsichord & strings, 1961; 3 sets parts (Box 58, Folder 140)
  - Seven Songs of Love [Robert Graves], 1961; lb: (Box 59, Folder 141)
  - Music for a Wedding, 1962; lb: (Box 59, Folder 142)
  - Symphony No. 2, 1962; lb: (Box 59, Folder 143)
  - Symphony No. 2, 1962; lb: (Box 59, Folder 144)
  - Variations, violin & piano, 1963; lb: (Box 59, Folder 145)
  - Ohio, overture for symphony orchestra, 1963; lb: (Box 59, Folder 146)
  - Chorale, organ [for Whit Griswold], 1963; lb: (Box 59, Folder 147)
  - Fanfare for Opening of the Art & Architecture Building, Yale University, 1963; positive photocopy of typescript, score (Box 59, Folder 148)
  - Jubilate Deo, for men's chorus & organ, 1965; lb: (Box 59, Folder 149)
  - Quintet, oboe & strings, 1966; lb: (Box 60, Folder 150)
    Highgate Press publication, score & parts 1966
  - Songs for Rose Jackson, 1966 (Box 60, Folder 150)
    "The Sister's Lullaby" [Padraic Colum]
    "You Stay For a While Beside Me" [Padraic Colum]
    "It Was a Lover and His Lass" [Shakespeare]
    "Who Is Sylvia" [Shakespeare]
    "O Mistress Mine" [Shakespeare]
    "Take, O Take Those Lips Away" [Shakespeare]
  - Songs for Rose Jackson, 1966; pencil, ink, typescript sketches [including sketches for songs never completed] (Box 60, Folder 151)
  - Songs for Rose Jackson, 1966; lb: (Box 60, Folder 152)
  - Wie Sie die Zehnsucht ["The Wilson Cantata"], lb: (Box 60, Folder 153)
  - Sketches, pages numbered 1-43, dating from 1955 (Box 60, Folder 154)
  - Sketches, originally housed in folder marked "Sketches on piano, Nov. 12, 1966" (Box 60, Folder 155)
  - Unidentified sketches (Box 61, Folder 156-158)
  - Index cards, containing data on Porter works, including dates of performance (Box 61, Folder 159)
- Works Copied or Arranged by Porter, Series XI; 1 Box
  This series contains several works of other composers which were copied and/or arranged for instruments by Porter.
  - Violin Sonata No. 6, E major. Loure, Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Piano Sonata, Op. 49, No. 2. Tempo di Menuetto., Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    Arranged for strings
  - Symphony No. 6 (Le Matin)., Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809; Three wind parts (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Ein Nachklang, Op. 8, No. 4 [orchestra]., Jensen, A.; Score. (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Orfeo. Excerpts. Arranged for brass & strings., Monteverdi, Claudio, 1567-1643; lb: (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - The Star-Spangled Banner. Arranged for strings., Smith, J.S.; lb: (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Untitled tune, arranged by Porter for piano (?), 2 positive photocopies of typescript score (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Manuscript & Photocopy Works of Other Composers, 1918-1960; Series XII; 4 Boxes
  These works have been listed alphabetically by composer. The large majority of them are photocopies of manuscripts. Inscriptions or dedications from the composers which appear on the scores have been noted in the register.
  - Little Suite, for oboe, English horn, bassoon, 1949; Albritton, Sherodd R.; positive photocopy, score & parts (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - String Quartet No. 2, 1939; Ames, William T.; positive photocopy, score (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Wachet auf, ruft uns die Stimme [for 2 pianos], No date; Bailey, Parker, 1902-1982; 2 positive photocopies, score (Box 63, Folder 2)
    arrangement
  - No. 3, Op. 35, for violin & piano, 1946; Bentzon, Niels Viggo; positive photocopy, score & part (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Trio, for 2 violins & viola, 1948; Boatwright, Howard, 1918-1999; positive photocopy, viola part [with additions & corrections] (Box 63, Folder 2)
    Valley Music Press publication, 1st violin part
  - Short Settings for Missa Cantata (voices & organ), No date; Cardew, F.A.; positive photocopy, score (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Sonata [violin or violin & piano], No date; Chanler, Theodore, 1902-1961; ink manuscript, violin part [many pencil notations] (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Suite, for viola & piano, 1937; Creston, Paul, 1906-1985; positive photocopy, score (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Suite IV, for piano, 1956; 1960; Davison, John; positive photocopy, score (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Untitled piece, for 2 violins & viola, No date; Donovan, Richard, 1891-1970; positive photocopy, score & parts (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Duo, for oboe (or violin or flute) and viola (or clarinet), 1945; Etler, Alvin, 1913-1973; positive photocopy, score & clarinet part (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Sonata No. 2 for violin & piano, 1950; Fetler, Paul; positive photocopy [ink inscription], score & part (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Suite, for woodwinds & strings, 1947; Fuller, Dean; manuscript, score (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - "Think About Wheels" [women's chorus], 1953; Gerschefski, Edwin, 1909-1992; ditto copy, score (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - "Changing Shoes" [women's chorus], No date; Gerschefski, Edwin, 1909-1992; ditto copy, score (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Nocturne, for violoncello & piano, Op.41, No.2, No date; Gerschefski, Edwin, 1909-1992; positive photocopy, score & part (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Two Songs, mezzo soprano & strings, No date; Goeb, Roger, 1914-1997; positive photocopy, score (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Sonata, for viola alone, No date; Goeb, Roger, 1914-1997; positive photocopy, score (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Concertant III, viola & chamber ensemble, No date; Goeb, Roger, 1914-1997; positive photocopy, score (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Concertant III, viola & piano, No date; Goeb, Roger, 1914-1997; positive photocopy, score (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Trio, for violin, viola, violoncello, No date; Goeb, Roger, 1914-1997; positive photocopy, score (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Songs, 1948; Gratch, Olga; positive photocopy, score (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Suite For Trio (violin, cello, piano), No date; Griffis, Elliot, 1893-1967; positive photocopy, score & parts (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Recollections, for piano, 1959; Helps, Robert, 1928-2001; positive photocopy [ink inscription], score (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - The Demon of the Gibbet [male chorus], 1949; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; positive -photocopy, score (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Concerto Piccolo, for bassoon & piano, No date; Horak, A.; positive photocopy, score & part (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Five studies, for violin & piano, 1952; Layton, Billy Jim, 1924-2004; positive photocopy, score (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Prière pour la Paix [chorus & organ], 1940; Leonard, Clair; positive photocopy, score (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Street Scene from the ballet "Fifth Avenue" for 2 pianos, No date; Lubin, Ernest; positive photocopy, score (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Fugalities [female chorus], No date; MacColl, Hugh F.; positive photocopy, score (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - A Birthday Waltz, 1945; McLaughlin, Charles; manuscript (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - A Strange "Two vs. One", No date; McLaughlin, Charles; manuscript (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Sonata, violin & piano, 1929; Moore, Douglas, 1893-1969; lb: (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - String Quartet, No date; Moore, Douglas, 1893-1969; positive photocopy, parts (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - The Red Cross Spirit Speaks, 1919; Parker, Horatio (Box 64, Folder 10)
    H.W. Gray publication [signed copy]
  - Fixation, for oboe, three violas, cello, 1959; Pottle, Sam; positive photocopy, score (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Sonata, piano, No date; Randall, James; positive photocopy, score (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Te Deum Laudamus [voices & organ], 1955; Rhea, Arthur; positive photocopy, score (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - The Hollow Men [female voices, flute, strings], No date; Richards, Sally; 3 positive photocopies, score (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Canon & Fugue for Strings, No date; Riegger, Wallingford; positive photocopy, score (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Two String Quartets, Op. 5, No date; Sasonkin, M.D.; manuscript, parts (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Gavotte, for piano, No date; Schoettle, Elmer; positive photocopy, score (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Berceuse [song], 1918; Simonds, Bruce; manuscript, score (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Habanera, violin & piano, No date; Simonds, Bruce; lb: (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Mass, for small chorus, 1954; Sims, Ezra, 1928-2015; positive photocopy, score (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - String Quartet, 1959; Sims, Ezra, 1928-2015; positive photocopy, score & parts (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - The Cloak [song], 1960; Smith, Peter; positive photocopy, score (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Suite, for viola & piano, 1957-1959; Stevens, Halsey; positive photocopy, viola part (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Eight Introspections, piano, 1959; Thorne, Francis, 1922-; positive photocopy, score (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Sonatina, 2 violins, 1959; Thorne, Francis, 1922-; positive photocopy [ink inscription], score (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Introduction & Presto, for strings, No date; Van Vactor, David, 1906-1994; positive photocopy, score & parts (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - Nine Songs [Rilke], 1949; Weisgarber, Elliot, 1919-2001; positive photocopy, score (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Divertimento No.1, 2 violins & viola, 1950; Weisgarber, Elliot, 1919-2001; lb: (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Divertimento No. 2, 2 violins & viola, 1950; Weisgarber, Elliot, 1919-2001; lb: (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Trio, clarinet, violin & viola, 1950; Weisgarber, Elliot, 1919-2001; positive photocopy, score & parts (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - The Butterflys [song], No date; Wigglesworth, Frank, 1918-1996; positive photocopy, score (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Anne Gregory [song], No date; Wigglesworth, Frank, 1918-1996; positive photocopy, score (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Super Flumina Babilonis [SATB], No date; Wigglesworth, Frank, 1918-1996; positive photocopy, score (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - A Short Mass [SATB], No date; Wigglesworth, Frank, 1918-1996; positive photocopy, score (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Quintet for brass, No date; Wigglesworth, Frank, 1918-1996; positive photocopy, score (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - [Suite?], violin & piano, No date; Wigglesworth, Frank, 1918-1996; positive photocopy, score (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Petite Melody in G [piano?], No date; Unidentifiable composer; manuscript, score (Box 66, Folder 17)